so my mother and I took a trip last week
and we went to the coast which is not
actually that far away but it is over
the mountains and so the climate is
quite different over there it's a lot
more humid and rainy over here some of
our regions are the high desert so it's
a very different sort of environment I
focused mostly on having a really lovely
time with her of course but I did get
some things I wanted to share one thing
was that I went to a botanical garden
and I had the most amazing time it was
such a beautiful place and so I will
share a video of that soon however I did
have the best time antique shopping and
I don't think I've made a shopping
specific you know video on here it's not
really the genre that this channel falls
into however going thrift store shopping
secondhand shopping antique shopping all
those things I I love doing them I love
upcycling things as well most of things
in my home are second hand and you may
not think they are because I spend a lot
of time making them look you know really
nice and refurbishing them but I do
enjoy that it is a really fun hobby for
me especially when I can get a good deal
on something so I thought I would share
with you a little bit of a fun antique
find I found and my kind of process of
making it fit into my home I assume this
is not going to be everyone's cup of tea
but I did want to share this it was a
really fun experience and I just I
simply was excited about the whole
process so I thought I would invite you
to come and take shopping with me so I
will have to begin at the beginning
where I went to port gamble with my
mother and it is such a cute and quaint
little town that I used to visit when I
was much younger and so it was really
lovely to come back there and check out
some of the antique shops so I ended up
finding some very exciting things
including some chairs I think the moment
you see them you will understand why I
was so excited
[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
so this is one of the best things that
have happened on this trip and I am so
happy that I happen to walk into that
specific antique shop and find these I
am a very budget-minded person
especially when I am shopping for items
you know like for my home I don't like
to spend it is always so exciting when I
find what at least I perceive to be a
really good deal and to me 45 dollars
for three chairs and they have these uh
hand woven seat covers and I can only
assume these are hand carved designs you
know maybe not if you recognize these
chairs or they look like something that
you found at Target lately do let me
know because that would be very
disappointing but I do assume they are
at least rather unique I don't know
anything about them but I do think they
are just so beautiful and just unlike
anything I've ever found in an antique
shop and
I think that if you've watched this
channel for enough time you would agree
that these are very Paula slash Cottage
fairy chairs I think they fit they fit
the fairy tale theme perfectly and the
good thing is that I wouldn't have
probably purchased these chairs unless I
actually needed chairs for my home but
we do have this old little round
thrifted table with a couple plain white
chairs that you probably saw in my
Cottage tour recently and I wanted to
put some new chairs there it's just
enough room for about three chairs and I
want to now paint the table to match
these chairs
and that is my goal I'm going to go to
the hardware store because even though
we are a very small town the one thing
we do have to have is a hardware store
especially when you live in a rural area
and you have to do a lot of your own
repairs and so I'm gonna go check out
what they have and see if I can find
some paint
oh I forgot I I found something else at
a Goodwill so let's let's bring that
over
so I also found this jar at a Goodwill I
think it was nine dollars and I don't
know it just it spoke to me it has this
textured surface that makes me assume at
least some of this perhaps was hand done
but I don't know you'll have to tell me
if there's anyone out there who knows
Something About Antiques or jars you can
let me know if all that textured surface
means that someone hand painted this or
if it's just some sort of amazing
machine I don't know about there is so
much texture to it and on the bottom it
says Satsuma and it says it was from
China so it is just so beautiful I'm
just Enchanted by it it is such a
gorgeous gorgeous design anyway I'm
gonna leave now I've kept getting
distracted so I'm gonna go find some
paint and I will see you very very soon
goodbye
[Music]
thank you
so I got this blue color thinking it was
going to complement quite well these
chairs and I don't think it doesn't
complement them however
I think that these chairs are more
earthy in their tone
and they're kind of rustic and they're
painted a little unevenly and this table
I think now looks like too too nice if
that makes sense
um I think the color is just too crisp
and I think something darker and more
weathered would complement things better
so
so I'm gonna try
adding a layer of paint that is darker
and then sand papering it a little bit
to see if I can create a more rustic
weathered look
but I don't know if that's gonna work
I've never done this before so we're
gonna we're gonna just have to
experiment and see
[Music]
this is so stressful I don't know if I'm
ruining it or if I'm making it better
[Music]
so I think I'm going to stop here
because
um I'm a little intimidated and unsure
whether or not I just ruined this table
or I improved it
um I think in a few days time I will
probably know the answer and we will
make a decision then but at the very
least I do think it matches the chairs
so in that way we have succeeded so I'm
going to roll this inside now after it
dries a little more and set it all up
[Music]
thank you
so I hope you enjoyed this little uh
project crafting antique shopping update
I've wanted to make some videos on a
larger variety of topics some that
interest me quite a bit one of them
being antique shopping and also
repurposing old furniture thank you so
much for all who have supported my Etsy
shop I have a special promotion going on
so you can check out the details down
below I appreciate the support it makes
all the difference for this Channel
please give me recommendations for
decorating and any other ideas you have
I hope you spend a little bit of time
doing something creative today and I am
sending you all the well wishes and I
will see you very soon goodbye